AJAY RANWA

24 Hubert Rd, London E6 3EY · +44 7741772079

Email-ID· LinkedIn Profile · GitHub

IT Professional with experience of working as a Junior SQL Developer and have good hands-on experience on SQL and python Language which helped me to get practical knowledge of this job. I have Experience working as a Campus Ambassador that highlights Leadership qualities and communication skills.

EXPERIENCE

DEC 2021- APRIL 2022

JUNIOR SQL DEVELOPER, W3TECHNOSOFT

SKILLS: MICROSOFT EXCEL, DATABASE QUERIES, RELATIONAL DATABASES, MYSQL, SQL SERVER INTEGRATION SERVICES (SSIS), AND T-SQL STORED PROCEDURES.

Tasks :- Worked on relational databases and SQL programming, with jobs including SQL Server Integration Services (SSIS) for data integration and data transformation solutions. Handled all day-to-day tasks and developed stored procedures to assist the organization in dealing with data in a more efficient manner.

DEC 2022- PRESENT

DATA ANALYTICS TRAINEE, TRAINITY

VIRTUAL INTERNSHIP

Tasks: This is a 100 days of projects building workshop provided by trainity for improving our sql and analytics techniques.

Jobs in it are acquiring data from primary and secondary sources, and finding, analysing, and interpreting data patterns.

MAY 2021-JUNE 2021

DATA SCIENCE & BUSINESS ANALYTICS, THE SPARKS FOUNDATION

VIRTUAL INTERNSHIP

Tasks: Things we perform here are to collect data and train a machine with that data and predict the outcomes with the test data.

Our works include day to day tasks perform.

JAN 2021 - FEB 2021

CAMPUS AMBASSADOR, EDFOUL

VIRTUAL INTERNSHIP

Tasks :- Helped our team to build various kinds of led they were working on. Learnt good communication skills and can up with a good leadership quality.

NOV 2020 - DEC 2021

VOLUNTEERING, YOUTH EMPOWERMENT FOUNDATION

VIRTUAL INTERNSHIP

Tasks: - Making awareness about our organization to people who don't know about it. Collection of donations for people's who need help in lock down.

EDUCATION

MAY 2023 - PRESENT

MSC COMPUTER SCIENCE, UNIVERSITY OF EAST LONDON

ONGOING UNIVERSITY

2017 - NOV 2021

B. TECH (HONS.), COMPUTER SCIENCE, BHARTIYA INSTITUTE OF ENGINEERING &

TECHNOLOGY
Percentage: 77.00%

YEAR OF COMPLETION: 2017

SENIOR SECONDARY (XII), NARAYANA JUNIOR COLLAGE (TELENGANA BOARD)

Percentage: 88.70%

YEAR OF COMPLETION: 2015

SECONDARY (X), TAGORE INTERNATIONAL SCHOOL (CBSE BOARD)

CGPA: 8.00/10

PROJECTS

- Library Management System (Python)
- Color Detection (Python)
- Real Estate Company prediction (Machine Learning)
- Voice assistant (Python)
- Flappy Bird (Pygame)
- Fake News Detection (Machine Learning)

SKILLS

- SQL
- Microsoft Excel
- C Programming
- English Proficiency (Spoken)

- Python
- HTML
- CSS
- Machine Learning